Hello. Today we will be discussing the topic parameter efficient transformers. So let's
안녕하세요. 오늘 우리는 주제 매개변수 효율적인 변환기에 대해 논의할 것입니다. 그럼
begin. Parameter efficient transformers are modifications of the standard transformer
시작하다. 매개변수 효율적인 변압기는 표준 변압기를 수정한 것입니다.
model designed to reduce the number of trainable parameters while maintaining the performance.
성능을 유지하면서 훈련 가능한 매개변수의 수를 줄이도록 설계된 모델입니다.
These methods aim to make transformers more computationally efficient and easier to deploy
이러한 방법은 변환기를 보다 계산적으로 효율적이고 배포하기 쉽게 만드는 것을 목표로 합니다.
in a resource constrained environment. In the first half of the presentation, we will
자원이 제한된 환경에서. 발표 전반부에는
be covering four research papers discussing their prerequisites, concepts, experiments
전제 조건, 개념, 실험을 논의하는 4개의 연구 논문을 다루어야 합니다.
and results of each of them. In paper one, parameter efficient transfer learning for
그리고 각각의 결과. 논문 1에서는 매개변수 효율적인 전이 학습을 수행했습니다.
NLP, we will be covering water transfer learning, teacher based versus fine tuning, adapter
NLP, 우리는 물 전달 학습, 교사 기반 대 미세 조정, 어댑터를 다룰 것입니다.
tuning and architecture. In paper two, Laura, low rank adaptation of language models, large
튜닝과 아키텍처. 논문 2에서 Laura는 언어 모델의 낮은 순위 적응, 대규모
language models, we will talk about fine tuning, LLMs and parameter efficient approach, adapter
언어 모델에서는 미세 조정, LLM 및 매개변수 효율적인 접근 방식, 어댑터에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
modules and prefix tuning, intrinsic dimension and intrinsic rank and Laura. In paper three,
모듈 및 접두사 조정, 고유 차원 및 고유 순위 및 Laura. 세 번째 논문에서는
it's not just the size that matters. Small language models are also few short learners.
중요한 것은 크기만이 아닙니다. 소규모 언어 모델은 짧은 학습자도 거의 없습니다.
We'll discuss zero short learning versus a few short learning, pet pattern exploiting
우리는 짧은 학습이 없는 것과 몇 가지 짧은 학습, 애완동물 패턴 활용에 대해 논의할 것입니다.
training, IPET, iterative variant of pet and pet with multiple masks. For paper four, making
훈련, IPET, 애완동물의 반복 변형 및 여러 마스크를 사용한 애완동물. 종이 4개를 만들기 위해
pre-trained language models better few short learners, topics are LMBFF, better few short
사전 훈련된 언어 모델은 짧은 학습자가 적을수록 좋음, 주제는 LMBFF, 짧은 학습자가 적을수록 좋음
fine tuning of language models, prompt based fine tuning, automatic prompt generation and
언어 모델 미세 조정, 프롬프트 기반 미세 조정, 자동 프롬프트 생성 및
fine tuning with demonstrations. In paper one, parameter efficient transfer learning
시연을 통해 미세 조정. 논문 1에서는 매개변수 효율적인 전이 학습
for NLP, let's start. So what is transfer learning? It is machine learning method where
NLP의 경우 시작해 보겠습니다. 그렇다면 전이학습이란 무엇인가? 머신러닝 방식입니다.
a model developed for one task is used as a starting point for a model on a different
하나의 작업을 위해 개발된 모델이 다른 작업의 모델을 위한 출발점으로 사용됩니다.
but related task. Basically, the concept is that there is no need to reinvent the wheel
하지만 관련 작업. 기본적으로 개념은 바퀴를 재발명할 필요가 없다는 것입니다.
but to use the wheel to make a car. This approach is more efficient and versatile as it can
하지만 바퀴를 사용하여 자동차를 만드는 것입니다. 이 접근 방식은 더 효율적이고 다재다능합니다.
be used in many similar tasks and mostly results in higher performance. To understand the key
많은 유사한 작업에 사용되며 대부분 더 높은 성능을 발휘합니다. 핵심을 이해하려면
difference between feature based and fine tuning, let's take an example. For someone
기능 기반과 미세 조정의 차이점에 대해 예를 들어 보겠습니다. 누군가를 위해
like me who comes from India where multiple languages are spoken, it is easier to learn
나처럼 여러 언어를 사용하는 인도에서 왔기 때문에 배우기가 더 쉽습니다.
a new language as many languages share similar features. And I can use the same understanding
많은 언어가 유사한 기능을 공유하므로 새로운 언어입니다. 그리고 나도 같은 이해를 사용할 수 있습니다
and concepts I have already learned and use them to my benefit, to learn a new language.
그리고 나는 이미 배운 개념을 나에게 유익하게 사용하고 새로운 언어를 배웁니다.
For a friend of mine who only speaks one language, it could be comparatively difficult to learn
한 가지 언어만 구사하는 친구에게는 배우기가 비교적 어려울 수 있습니다.
a completely new language as the similarities between both languages could be limited, leading
두 언어 간의 유사성이 제한될 수 있으므로 완전히 새로운 언어
to a requirement of more resources and time to get good at any new language. In feature
새로운 언어를 능숙하게 익히려면 더 많은 자원과 시간이 필요합니다. 기능 있음
based, the original function phi w is used as the base to train on new parameters V,
기반으로, 원래 함수 phi w는 새로운 매개변수 V에 대해 학습하기 위한 기반으로 사용됩니다.
making the new function as sky V phi w X. There is almost no change made to the original
sky V phi w X로 새로운 기능을 만듭니다. 원본에는 거의 변화가 없습니다.
function and its parameters. In fine tuning, the later half of the function is modified
함수와 그 매개변수. 미세 조정에서는 기능 후반부가 수정됩니다.
for the new parameters, where new parameters are introduced and old parameters are used
새 매개변수의 경우 새 매개변수가 도입되고 이전 매개변수가 사용됩니다.
to tune the model. A new concept of adapter tuning is introduced here, where the original
모델을 조정합니다. 여기에 새로운 개념의 어댑터 튜닝이 도입되었습니다.
function and its parameters are frozen during the time of training and new parameters are
함수와 해당 매개변수는 학습 중에 동결되며 새 매개변수는
added in between the function in the form of adapter modules. It is like taking a time
어댑터 모듈 형태로 기능 사이에 추가되었습니다. 시간을 보내는 것과 같습니다
machine and adding only a few minutes of learning a new language every day in your entire lifetime
기계를 사용하고 평생 동안 매일 새로운 언어를 배우는 데 몇 분만 추가하면 됩니다.
without modifying the course of your life and the core understanding and learning of your
당신의 삶의 과정과 당신의 핵심 이해와 학습을 수정하지 않고
original language. On the left is a basic transformer layer architecture that we have
원어. 왼쪽에는 우리가 가지고 있는 기본 변환기 레이어 아키텍처가 있습니다.
modified by adding adapter modules in between. On the right is a view of the adapter modules,
사이에 어댑터 모듈을 추가하여 수정되었습니다. 오른쪽에는 어댑터 모듈의 모습이 있습니다.
which we have used. Let us take a deeper look into each of them. In the transformer layer,
우리가 사용한 것. 각각에 대해 더 자세히 살펴보겠습니다. 트랜스포머 레이어에서는
the primary sub layer is the multi-headed attention layer, which processes the input
기본 하위 레이어는 입력을 처리하는 다중 헤드 주의 레이어입니다.
data for the model. Then comes the feed forward layer, where the data is processed using the
모델에 대한 데이터입니다. 그런 다음 피드 포워드 계층이 나오며, 여기서 데이터는 다음을 사용하여 처리됩니다.
attention mechanism. We will discuss the adapter layer in a bit. Then we see a plus sign, which
주의 메커니즘. 우리는 어댑터 계층에 대해 조금 논의할 것입니다. 그런 다음 더하기 기호가 표시됩니다.
is the skip connection. Here, the decision is made whether the output of the adapter or feed
건너뛰기 연결입니다. 여기서는 어댑터의 출력인지 피드의 출력인지 결정됩니다.
forward layer is to be added to the original input layer or sub layer. This helps in preserving
순방향 레이어는 원래 입력 레이어 또는 하위 레이어에 추가됩니다. 이는 보존에 도움이 됩니다.
the information from earlier stages and making the decision whether this new process data is
이전 단계의 정보를 수집하고 이 새로운 프로세스 데이터가 적합한지 여부를 결정합니다.
to be added to the network or not. Finally, we have the layer normalization, which normalizes
네트워크에 추가할지 여부를 결정합니다. 마지막으로, 정규화하는 레이어 정규화가 있습니다.
the combined output provided by its previous sub layers. The adapter modules, which are added
이전 하위 레이어에서 제공한 결합된 출력입니다. 추가된 어댑터 모듈
to the transformer layer, have a bottleneck architecture to it. This specific architecture
변환기 계층에 병목 현상이 있는 아키텍처가 있습니다. 이 특정 아키텍처
helps us add only a few parameters, ranging between 0.5 to 8%, making the total number of
0.5~8% 범위의 몇 가지 매개변수만 추가하여 총
parameters as 2MD plus D plus M. The number of new parameters that are being added can be
매개변수는 2MD + D + M입니다. 추가되는 새 매개변수의 수는 다음과 같습니다.
controlled by increasing the size of this adapter module. Finally, there is a skip connection,
이 어댑터 모듈의 크기를 늘려 제어됩니다. 마지막으로 건너뛰기 연결이 있습니다.
where the impact of the newly added parameters are controlled by initializing it to a near zero
새로 추가된 매개변수의 영향은 거의 0으로 초기화하여 제어됩니다.
at the start and slowly increasing it over the training. The goal of this paper is to help
처음에는 훈련을 진행하면서 점차적으로 증가시킵니다. 이 문서의 목표는 도움을 주는 것입니다.
build compact and extensible systems that give good results on multiple similar downstream tasks,
여러 유사한 다운스트림 작업에서 좋은 결과를 제공하는 컴팩트하고 확장 가능한 시스템을 구축합니다.
where the new data that is coming into the system is unknown at the time of training.
훈련 시점에는 시스템에 들어오는 새로운 데이터를 알 수 없습니다.
For this, the authors have used 26 different classification tasks to benchmark the results
이를 위해 저자는 결과를 벤치마킹하기 위해 26개의 서로 다른 분류 작업을 사용했습니다.
using BERT. Gluebenchmark is an important benchmarking tool, which is widely used to train
BERT를 사용합니다. Gluebenchmark는 교육에 널리 사용되는 중요한 벤치마킹 도구입니다.
and evaluate such natural language understanding systems. The key feature is that it is model
그러한 자연어 이해 시스템을 평가합니다. 가장 큰 특징은 모델이라는 점입니다.
agnostic and has a leaderboard and dashboard to benchmark and showcase the results.
불가지론적이며 결과를 벤치마킹하고 보여줄 수 있는 리더보드와 대시보드가 ​​있습니다.
Squad, the Stanford question answering data set, was also utilized in this paper. It comprises of
본 논문에서는 Stanford 질의응답 데이터셋인 Squad도 활용하였다. 그것은 다음과 같이 구성됩니다
107,785 question answer pairs from Wikipedia articles in its 1.1 version.
1.1 버전의 Wikipedia 기사에 있는 107,785개의 질문 답변 쌍입니다.
On the gluebenchmarking tool, the BERT model with adapter modules matches the performance of fine
글루벤치마킹 도구에서 어댑터 모듈이 포함된 BERT 모델은 정밀한 성능과 일치합니다.
tuning and by only utilizing around 3% of the new parameters, the AutoML benchmark results are
튜닝하고 새 매개변수 중 약 3%만 활용하면 AutoML 벤치마크 결과는 다음과 같습니다.
also good. BERT based with adapters utilizes only 1.14% new parameters and reaches 73.3% accuracy,
또한 좋다. 어댑터 기반 BERT는 1.14%의 새로운 매개변수만 활용하고 73.3%의 정확도에 도달합니다.
while BERT based fine tuning uses 100% new parameters and reaches 73.7% accuracy.
BERT 기반 미세 조정은 100% 새로운 매개변수를 사용하고 73.7% 정확도에 도달합니다.
The graph on the right also shows that the validation accuracy with adapter modules can be
오른쪽 그래프는 또한 어댑터 모듈의 검증 정확도가 다음과 같을 수 있음을 보여줍니다.
similar to fine tuning while utilizing 100 times less number of new parameters.
100배 적은 수의 새로운 매개변수를 활용하면서 미세 조정과 유사합니다.
Paper 2 is Laura, low-ranked adaptation of large language models.
논문 2는 Laura, 대규모 언어 모델의 하위 적응입니다.
This equation is used to predict the next word in a phrase. Here, yt is the next word and its
이 방정식은 구문의 다음 단어를 예측하는 데 사용됩니다. 여기, yt가 다음 단어이고 그
probability is calculated based on the previous words y0 to yt minus 1 and the parameters 5.
확률은 이전 단어 y0에서 yt 빼기 1과 매개변수 5를 기반으로 계산됩니다.
In the fine tuning, this equation is altered by replacing 5 with new parameter weights y0 plus
미세 조정에서 이 방정식은 5를 새로운 매개변수 가중치 y0+로 대체하여 변경됩니다.
delta 5, where the dimension of delta 5 and 5 are not the same. In the parameter efficient approach,
델타 5와 델타 5의 차원은 동일하지 않습니다. 매개변수 효율적인 접근법에서는
this is further altered by multiplying delta 5 with theta, which has a much smaller dimension than
이는 델타 5와 세타를 곱하여 추가로 변경됩니다. 세타는 다음보다 훨씬 작은 차원을 갖습니다.
5 and 5 naught. This is approximately 10,000 times smaller than 5 naught.
5와 5는 없습니다. 이는 50보다 약 10,000배 더 작습니다.
As we just learned about adapter modules, a question might arise that can we not use
방금 어댑터 모듈에 대해 배웠듯이, 우리가 사용할 수 없는 질문이 생길 수도 있습니다.
adapter modules in LLMs like GPT-3? And the answer is yes, we can, but adapter modules need to be
GPT-3과 같은 LLM의 어댑터 모듈? 대답은 '예'입니다. 가능합니다. 하지만 어댑터 모듈은
processed sequentially, which leads to high inference latency and additional depth to our
순차적으로 처리되므로 추론 지연 시간이 길어지고 데이터에 깊이가 더해집니다.
approach in large modules like GPT-3. Let's address another question regarding prefix tuning here.
GPT-3과 같은 대규모 모듈에서 접근합니다. 여기서 접두사 조정에 관한 또 다른 질문을 다루겠습니다.
In the later half of the video, we will look into prefix tuning, but I can just give a brief
영상 후반부에는 프리픽스 튜닝에 대해 살펴보겠지만 간략하게만 말씀드리자면
for now. In prefix tuning, we add instructions at the start of the training process and freeze
지금은. 접두사 조정에서는 학습 프로세스 시작 시 지침을 추가하고 동결합니다.
the original parameters, but this will lead to inconsistent results and a difficulty to optimize
그러나 이로 인해 일관되지 않은 결과가 발생하고 최적화가 어려워집니다.
the entire approach. Also, we will have to add a prompt before each input, which would limit
전체 접근 방식. 또한 각 입력 앞에 프롬프트를 추가해야 합니다.
length of the tasks. We wish to process with the model. Hence, these two approaches are possible,
작업의 길이. 모델로 처리하고 싶습니다. 따라서 이 두 가지 접근 방식이 가능합니다.
but come with their own flaws. Let's understand two key concepts we would require in this approach.
그러나 그 자체의 결함도 있습니다. 이 접근 방식에 필요한 두 가지 주요 개념을 이해해 보겠습니다.
Number one, intrinsic dimension, which refers to the minimum number of parameters needed to get
첫 번째, 본질적인 차원은 다음을 얻는 데 필요한 최소 매개변수 수를 나타냅니다.
the performance similar to the full model. It is basically the simplest version of the model
전체 모델과 유사한 성능. 기본적으로 모델의 가장 간단한 버전입니다.
that does similar level of work. Second concept is intrinsic rank,
비슷한 수준의 작업을 수행합니다. 두 번째 개념은 본질적인 순위입니다.
which is the complexity of freedom in a particular component of the neural network.
이는 신경망의 특정 구성 요소에 대한 자유의 복잡성입니다.
Basically, it indicates the minimum number of dimensions needed to represent the important
기본적으로 중요한 내용을 표현하는 데 필요한 최소 차원 수를 나타냅니다.
information in that component of the neural network. These concepts are usually paired together,
신경망의 해당 구성 요소에 있는 정보입니다. 이러한 개념은 일반적으로 서로 짝을 이루며,
where we find the intrinsic dimension for the whole architecture and the intrinsic rank at
여기에서 전체 아키텍처의 본질적인 차원과 본질적인 순위를 찾을 수 있습니다.
each step to optimize our approach to use the least number of features.
각 단계는 최소한의 기능을 사용하도록 접근 방식을 최적화합니다.
This is the main concept that is being utilized in GARA. Here, the pre-trained weights are frozen
GARA에서 활용되고 있는 주요 컨셉입니다. 여기서는 사전 훈련된 가중치가 고정되어 있습니다.
during the time of the training, and the key parameters that are being added to the model
학습 중에 모델에 추가되는 주요 매개변수
are added in a matrix multiplication format represented by A cross B matrices here.
여기서는 A 교차 B 행렬로 표시되는 행렬 곱셈 형식으로 추가됩니다.
The intrinsic rank, which we just discussed, R is much lower than both D and K, which are original
방금 논의한 고유 순위인 R은 원래의 D와 K보다 훨씬 낮습니다.
dimension length that was being utilized by the neural network. Here, B is initialized as zero,
신경망에서 활용되고 있던 차원 길이입니다. 여기서 B는 0으로 초기화되고,
and A is initialized in a random Gaussian manner, and this is done so as to feed the model with very
A는 임의의 가우스 방식으로 초기화되며 이는 모델에 매우 많은 정보를 제공하기 위해 수행됩니다.
less number of new parameters at the start and escape eventually to reduce the need to redo
다시 실행해야 할 필요성을 줄이기 위해 시작 및 이스케이프 시 새 매개변수 수가 줄어듭니다.
in hyperparameters. Finally, the forward pass using LARA, which is W0x plus BAx has a lower rank
하이퍼파라미터에서. 마지막으로 W0x + BAx인 LARA를 사용한 정방향 패스는 순위가 더 낮습니다.
and uses much less number of parameters than usual. The experiments in this paper were conducted
평소보다 훨씬 적은 수의 매개변수를 사용합니다. 본 논문에서 수행된 실험은
using Robberta, Debberta, GPT-2, and GPT-3 was finally used for comparison. This was done over
최종적으로 Robberta, Debberta, GPT-2, GPT-3을 사용하여 비교하였다. 이건 끝났어
the glue benchmarking tool and various datasets like Vicky STL, SAMSUM, A2A, NLG, Dart, and Web
글루 벤치마킹 도구 및 Vicky STL, SAMSUM, A2A, NLG, Dart 및 Web과 같은 다양한 데이터 세트
Energy. These are some commonly used datasets and benchmarking tools to test natural language
에너지. 다음은 자연어를 테스트하기 위해 일반적으로 사용되는 데이터 세트 및 벤치마킹 도구입니다.
understanding systems. On the glue benchmark, we can see the approach using Robberta based with
시스템 이해. 접착제 벤치마크에서 우리는 Robberta를 기반으로 한 접근 방식을 볼 수 있습니다.
LARA only utilizes 0.3 million new parameters to result in an 87.2% accuracy using the least
LARA는 30만 개의 새로운 매개변수만 활용하여 최소한의 사용으로 87.2%의 정확도를 얻습니다.
number of parameters, other than the approach with bit width, which results in a much lower
비트 폭을 사용하는 접근 방식과 달리 매개변수 수가 훨씬 적습니다.
accuracy of 85.2%. And in the A2E NLG challenge with GPT-2, the approach with GPT-2 medium with
정확도 85.2%. 그리고 GPT-2를 사용한 A2E NLG 챌린지에서는 GPT-2 매체를 사용한 접근 방식이
LARA uses only 0.35 million new parameters to give the highest accuracy in all cases when compared
LARA는 비교 시 모든 경우에 대해 가장 높은 정확도를 제공하기 위해 35만 개의 새로운 매개변수만을 사용합니다.
to fine tuning which used 354.9 to million new parameters to give a lower accuracy. A similar
정확도를 낮추기 위해 354.9~100만 개의 새로운 매개변수를 사용하는 미세 조정을 수행했습니다. 비슷한
trend can be seen in the GPT-2 large trainable parameters and accuracy with LARA outperforming
LARA가 우수한 성능을 보이는 GPT-2의 대규모 훈련 가능한 매개변수와 정확성에서 추세를 볼 수 있습니다.
other approaches in most cases. When LARA is utilized with GPT-3, we can see it only uses
대부분의 경우 다른 접근 방식. LARA를 GPT-3와 함께 활용하면
37.7 million and 4.7 million new parameters to reach a slightly higher accuracy when compared
3,770만 개와 470만 개의 새로운 매개변수로 비교했을 때 약간 더 높은 정확도에 도달
to fine tuning with 175 billion new parameters. These trends are mapped out on the graphs on
1,750억 개의 새로운 매개변수로 미세 조정이 가능합니다. 이러한 추세는 다음 그래프에 표시됩니다.
the right as well where LARA outperforms all the other approaches in terms of accuracy.
LARA가 정확성 측면에서 다른 모든 접근 방식보다 뛰어난 성능을 발휘하는 경우도 마찬가지입니다.
Paper 3 is not just a size that matters, small language models are also few short learners.
Paper 3은 크기만 중요한 것이 아니며, 작은 언어 모델도 짧은 학습자가 거의 없습니다.
Let's firstly understand zero short learning. This is the approach when a model is trained for
먼저 제로 단기 학습에 대해 알아보겠습니다. 이는 모델을 훈련할 때의 접근 방식입니다.
a variety of tasks and is later applied to a new task and given no new examples to learn from.
다양한 작업을 수행하고 나중에 새로운 작업에 적용되며 배울 수 있는 새로운 예제가 제공되지 않습니다.
In this, the model relies on its general understanding and knowledge gained during
이 모델은 학습 과정에서 얻은 일반적인 이해와 지식에 의존합니다.
the original training to make predictions about the new task. Few short learning is
새로운 작업에 대해 예측하기 위한 원래의 훈련입니다. 짧은 학습은 거의 없습니다.
similar to zero short learning but a few examples related to the new task are used to fine tune
제로 단기 학습과 유사하지만 새로운 작업과 관련된 몇 가지 예를 사용하여 미세 조정합니다.
this model. This usually results in better accuracy than zero short learning due to the new examples.
이 모델. 이는 일반적으로 새로운 예제로 인해 제로 단기 학습보다 더 나은 정확도를 가져옵니다.
Let's consider a model when trained on English language data set is applied for sentiment
영어 데이터 세트를 학습하여 감성에 적용할 때 모델을 고려해 보겠습니다.
analysis on French language data directly then it is zero short learning but when the same model
프랑스어 데이터를 직접 분석하면 학습 시간이 제로이지만 동일한 모델을 사용하면
is fine tuned on a few examples which contain documents with French language in it then it is
프랑스어가 포함된 문서가 포함된 몇 가지 예를 정밀하게 조정한 다음
few short learning. Pet or pattern exploiting training here an input x1 comma x2 is converted
짧은 학습이 거의 없습니다. 여기서 입력 x1 쉼표 x2가 변환되는 애완동물 또는 패턴 활용 훈련
to a closed question px and the probability qp y by x is derived for the possible choices of outputs
닫힌 질문 px에 대해 x에 의한 확률 qp y는 가능한 출력 선택에 대해 파생됩니다.
that fit the input to complete the closed question using a mass language model or mlm as given in
대량 언어 모델 또는 mlm을 사용하여 닫힌 질문을 완성하기 위한 입력에 맞는 것입니다.
the example here x1 is oil prices fallback and x2 is oil prices rise a yes or no needs to fit in
여기의 예에서 x1은 유가 하락이고 x2는 유가 상승입니다. 예 또는 아니오에 맞춰야 합니다.
the blank space between x1 and x2 to connect these inputs to complete the closed question.
x1과 x2 사이의 공백을 사용하여 이러한 입력을 연결하여 닫힌 질문을 완성하세요.
This is done using a pair of pattern verbalizer pairs or pvps which help map inputs to outputs
이는 입력을 출력으로 매핑하는 데 도움이 되는 한 쌍의 패턴 언어변환기 쌍 또는 pvps를 사용하여 수행됩니다.
here p maps inputs to closed question containing single mass and v is used to map each output
여기서 p는 단일 질량을 포함하는 닫힌 질문에 입력을 매핑하고 v는 각 출력을 매핑하는 데 사용됩니다.
to a token representing its task specific meaning in the pattern. qpy by x is calculating using the
패턴에서 작업별 의미를 나타내는 토큰입니다. qpy by x는 다음을 사용하여 계산됩니다.
raw position of vy that are the possible outputs to complete the closed question at the mass position
대량 위치에서 닫힌 질문을 완료하기 위해 가능한 출력인 vy의 원시 위치
in px as we're using future learning that is a less number of examples to fine tune the model
모델을 미세 조정하기 위해 더 적은 수의 예를 사용하는 미래 학습을 사용하므로 px 단위입니다.
we need multiple pvps and a combination of these is used to determine the output.
여러 pvp가 필요하며 이들의 조합을 사용하여 출력을 결정합니다.
These pvps are used to assign final probabilities to the unlabeled examples
이러한 pvps는 레이블이 지정되지 않은 예제에 최종 확률을 할당하는 데 사용됩니다.
resulting in a probability distribution of each unlabeled input to a possible output.
그 결과 레이블이 지정되지 않은 각 입력이 가능한 출력에 대한 확률 분포가 생성됩니다.
ipet or iterative variant of pet is similar to pet where the flow comprises of three main steps
ipet 또는 pet의 반복 변형은 흐름이 세 가지 주요 단계로 구성되는 pet과 유사합니다.
number one initial training where an ensemble of mlms are trained using pet as we just discussed
방금 논의한 것처럼 애완동물을 사용하여 mlms 앙상블을 훈련하는 첫 번째 초기 훈련입니다.
number two creating new training sets where each model in this ensemble uses a random subset of
두 번째는 이 앙상블의 각 모델이 무작위 하위 집합을 사용하는 새로운 훈련 세트를 만드는 것입니다.
models to label a set of unlabeled examples number three retraining models where each model is
레이블이 지정되지 않은 예제 집합에 레이블을 지정하는 모델 세 번째는 각 모델이 다음과 같은 재교육 모델입니다.
retrained on its newly created training set and step two and three are repeated multiple times by
새로 생성된 훈련 세트로 재훈련되고 2단계와 3단계가 여러 번 반복됩니다.
changing the size of the training set by adding more and more examples to it pet with multiple
훈련 세트에 더 많은 예제를 추가하여 훈련 세트의 크기를 변경합니다.
masks this is similar to pet with single mask just that the prediction word would be longer
마스크는 예측 단어가 더 길다는 점만 제외하면 단일 마스크를 사용하는 애완동물과 유사합니다.
and needs to be broken down into multiple masks just like the one in the example
예제에 나온 것과 같이 여러 개의 마스크로 나누어야 합니다.
here the input x is awful pizza it's followed by it was and multiple masks to form a closed question
여기서 입력 x는 끔찍한 피자입니다. 그 뒤에는 닫힌 질문을 형성하는 여러 마스크가 있습니다.
instead of mapping the input to outputs here they are mapped back to the possible outputs
여기에서는 입력을 출력으로 매핑하는 대신 가능한 출력으로 다시 매핑합니다.
and then the process is repeated to find the best set that fits the complete closed question
그런 다음 완전한 닫힌 질문에 맞는 최상의 세트를 찾기 위해 프로세스가 반복됩니다.
if we take the example of sentiment classification of restaurant reviews we can broadly divide the
레스토랑 리뷰의 감정 분류를 예로 들면,
reviews as positive that is plus one and negative that is minus one we calculate the probability of
리뷰가 플러스 1인 긍정적인 리뷰와 마이너스 1인 부정적인 리뷰로 평가될 확률을 계산합니다.
each word that can fit each part of the mask token for each set and finally recalculate the best token
각 세트에 대한 마스크 토큰의 각 부분에 맞을 수 있는 각 단어를 찾아 최종적으로 가장 좋은 토큰을 다시 계산합니다.
that fits the closed question pet is based on albert and the authors have used an advanced
닫힌 질문 애완동물에 맞는 것은 Albert를 기반으로 하며 저자는 고급 방법을 사용했습니다.
version of glue benchmark known as superglue this benchmarking tool contains more challenging tasks
superglue로 알려진 접착제 벤치마크 버전 이 벤치마킹 도구에는 더 어려운 작업이 포함되어 있습니다.
like bool cube popa etc the authors have developed a variation of superglue known as few glue to
bool Cube popa 등과 같이 저자는 몇 가지 접착제로 알려진 슈퍼 접착제의 변형을 개발했습니다.
evaluate language models like pet and gpt3 few glue was developed by randomly selecting 32
pet 및 gpt3와 같은 언어 모델을 평가합니다. 소수 접착제는 무작위로 32개를 선택하여 개발되었습니다.
examples from each superglue task to ensure consistent and controlled selection of the data
일관되고 통제된 데이터 선택을 보장하기 위한 각 초강력 접착제 작업의 예
they also created sets of unlabeled examples up to 20 000 for each task by removing labels
또한 라벨을 제거하여 각 작업에 대해 최대 20,000개의 라벨이 지정되지 않은 예시 세트를 만들었습니다.
from the original training sets to evaluate the models unsupervised and semi-supervised learning
비지도 및 준지도 학습 모델을 평가하기 위해 원래 훈련 세트에서
capabilities the results showcase that pet and ipad model outperforms on the 32 randomly selected
무작위로 선택된 32개의 애완동물 및 아이패드 모델이 성능을 능가하는 결과를 보여줍니다.
examples after training on few glue where albert xx large v2 uh than most of the gpt3 models on
Albert xx Large v2 uh 대부분의 gpt3 모델보다 몇 가지 접착제로 훈련한 후의 예
superglue these are some extended examples where pet outperforms or closely matches the accuracy
초강력 접착제 이것은 애완동물이 정확도를 능가하거나 거의 일치하는 확장된 예입니다.
of most in-use models today paper four is uh making pre-trained language models better few
오늘날 가장 많이 사용되는 모델 중 네 번째 논문은 사전 훈련된 언어 모델을 더 좋게 만드는 것입니다.
short learners this paper builds on the previous paper we discussed and introduces lmbf a better
짧은 학습자를 위해 이 문서는 우리가 논의한 이전 문서를 기반으로 하며 더 나은 lmbf를 소개합니다.
few short fine tuning of language models approach it's a three-step process which involves taking
언어 모델의 몇 가지 짧은 미세 조정은 다음을 포함하는 3단계 프로세스입니다.
the new task and automatically converting it into a prompt an example from each class of the
새 작업을 자동으로 프롬프트로 변환합니다.
training data is added to the prompt which is then fed to the lm we can see this as a task that
훈련 데이터가 프롬프트에 추가된 다음 작품에 입력되면 이를 다음과 같은 작업으로 볼 수 있습니다.
is an input which can be converted to a prompt which fits the basic format for the lm this prompt
이 프롬프트의 기본 형식에 맞는 프롬프트로 변환될 수 있는 입력입니다.
also includes examples from every class we can see that as one example from each positive and
또한 각 수업의 예가 포함되어 있으며 긍정적이고 긍정적인 각 수업의 한 예로 볼 수 있습니다.
negative class from reviews about the restaurant the first step is prompt based fine tuning the
레스토랑에 대한 리뷰에서 부정적인 등급 첫 번째 단계는 신속한 기반 미세 조정입니다.
input task is converted to fit the right format by the lm for example with uh the cls token at the
입력 작업은 예를 들어 uh의 cls 토큰을 사용하여 lm에 의해 올바른 형식에 맞게 변환됩니다.
start and set token in between the different inputs this input also contains the masked word
서로 다른 입력 사이에 시작 및 설정 토큰 이 입력에는 마스크된 단어도 포함됩니다.
which is the masked token this prompt is an extended answer for the possible uh direct input
이것은 마스킹된 토큰입니다. 이 프롬프트는 가능한 직접 입력에 대한 확장된 답변입니다.
like no reason to watch uh where the prompt would would be it was great or it was terrible
예를 들어, 어 어디에서 프롬프트가 나올지 지켜볼 이유가 없듯이 훌륭했거나 끔찍했습니다
these tasks can be classification or regression tasks for classification a single probability
이러한 작업은 단일 확률을 분류하기 위한 분류 또는 회귀 작업일 수 있습니다.
is calculated for the masked word to help classify task label space to individual words
작업 레이블 공간을 개별 단어로 분류하는 데 도움이 되도록 마스크된 단어에 대해 계산됩니다.
in the vocabulary based on the prompt for regression the final probability is the sum of all the
회귀 프롬프트에 기초한 어휘에서 최종 확률은 모든 확률의 합입니다.
probabilities of possible sets example positive and negatives the second step of uh automatic
가능한 세트의 확률 예 긍정 및 부정 두 번째 단계 어 자동
prompt generation is divided into two parts automatic selection of label words and automatic
프롬프트 생성은 라벨 단어 자동 선택과 자동 선택 두 부분으로 나뉩니다.
generation of templates in the automatic selection of label words a set of top k vocabulary words
레이블 단어 자동 선택에서 템플릿 생성 상위 k 어휘 단어 세트
is constructed for each class in automatic generation of templates the authors have used a large
저자가 대규모로 사용한 템플릿의 자동 생성에서 각 클래스에 대해 구성됩니다.
pre-trained text-to-text transformer t5 to input sentences from the training set and fill in
훈련 세트에서 문장을 입력하고 채우기 위한 사전 훈련된 텍스트-텍스트 변환기 t5
template tokens like x and y to create an initial template for the prompt uh all these
프롬프트에 대한 초기 템플릿을 생성하기 위한 x 및 y와 같은 템플릿 토큰 어 이 모든 것
templates are built using a label mapping scheme uh these uh help find the final output template
템플릿은 라벨 매핑 구성표를 사용하여 구축되었습니다. 어 이거 어 최종 출력 템플릿을 찾는 데 도움이 됩니다.
that best fits um this done like this is done by testing them on datasets d def
그게 가장 잘 맞습니다. 음 이것은 데이터 세트 d def에서 테스트하여 수행됩니다.
in the final step fine tuning of the llm takes place by taking the prompt generated before
마지막 단계에서는 이전에 생성된 프롬프트를 사용하여 llm의 미세 조정이 수행됩니다.
and extending it with uh examples of each class this can be seen in uh the example where no reason
그리고 이를 각 클래스의 예로 확장하면 이유가 없는 예에서 볼 수 있습니다.
to watch is the is the input and a template it was mask was added to it uh at the end of it
보는 것은 입력이고 마스크였던 템플릿이 마지막에 추가되었습니다.
and a positive demonstration of a fun ride it was great and a negative demonstration of
재미있는 라이딩에 대한 긍정적인 시연은 훌륭했고 부정적인 시연은 훌륭했습니다.
the drama discloses nothing it was terrible were also added to the prompt this is then
드라마는 아무것도 공개하지 않았습니다. 끔찍한 일도 프롬프트에 추가되었습니다.
repeated to fine tune the llm over the entire dataset to help with the few short learning
몇 가지 짧은 학습을 돕기 위해 전체 데이터 세트에 대해 LLM을 미세 조정하기 위해 반복되었습니다.
uh for the evaluation of uh this the authors use roberta large over eight single sentence and seven
어 평가를 위해 저자는 8개의 단일 문장과 7개의 문장에 대해 roberta Large를 사용합니다.
sentence pairs uh pair english tasks including eight tasks from the glue benchmark uh stand
문장 쌍 uh 쌍 영어 작업에는 접착제 벤치마크의 8개 작업이 포함됩니다 uh 스탠드
for language natural language uh inference snli and six other popular sentence classification
언어 자연어 어 추론 snli 외 6개의 인기 문장 분류
tasks uh and the average performance is measured across five different randomly sampled detrain
작업 어 그리고 평균 성능은 무작위로 샘플링된 5개의 서로 다른 디트레인에서 측정됩니다.
and d d def splits in the tables we can see the templates that were utilized for this
그리고 테이블의 dd def 분할을 통해 이에 사용된 템플릿을 볼 수 있습니다.
the results are great as we can see that this method outperforms prompt with zero short in
결과는 훌륭합니다. 이 방법은 숏이 전혀 없는 프롬프트보다 성능이 뛰어나다는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
context learning with fine tuning of gpd 3 in most of the cases um these results also show
대부분의 경우 gpd 3의 미세 조정을 통한 상황 학습 음 이 결과는 또한 보여줍니다
both automatic prompt generation and manual prompt generation outperform other models
자동 프롬프트 생성과 수동 프롬프트 생성 모두 다른 모델보다 성능이 뛰어남
these results show a fair comparison of this three-step approach with pet as discussed earlier
이러한 결과는 앞서 논의한 대로 애완동물과의 3단계 접근 방식이 공정하게 비교되었음을 보여줍니다.
and the graph shows the accuracy versus instances of standard fine tuning versus lmbff where the
그래프는 정확도 대 표준 미세 조정 인스턴스 대 lmbff를 보여줍니다.
latter outperforms the former i would highly encourage everyone to check out the code of
후자가 전자보다 성능이 뛰어납니다. 모든 사람이 코드를 확인하도록 적극 권장합니다.
all four papers on github as they are well documented and easy to use
github에 있는 네 가지 논문 모두 잘 문서화되어 있고 사용하기 쉽습니다.
and so now i'll be covering the second half of this presentation where i cover additional
이제 저는 이 프리젠테이션의 후반부를 다루겠습니다.
parameter efficient fine tuning methods that is prefix tuning prompt tuning and ia cubed
프리픽스 튜닝 프롬프트 튜닝과 ia 큐브 등 매개변수 효율적인 미세 조정 방법
and then i'll look at understanding peft more broadly and that's through a unified view of peft
그런 다음 peft를 더 광범위하게 이해하는 방법을 살펴보겠습니다. 이는 peft에 대한 통일된 관점을 통해 이루어집니다.
and comparing peft with full model fine tuning first i'll look at this paper that introduces
그리고 peft를 전체 모델 미세 조정과 비교하기 전에 먼저 소개하는 이 문서를 살펴보겠습니다.
prompt tuning and before i cover prompt tuning some background in prefix tuning is necessary
프롬프트 튜닝 및 프롬프트 튜닝을 다루기 전에 접두사 튜닝에 대한 배경 지식이 필요합니다.
where in prefix tuning we learn a small fixed set of additional parameters that is the prefixes
접두사 조정에서는 접두사인 작은 고정 추가 매개변수 세트를 학습합니다.
so to do prefix tuning we prepare some number of tunable prefix vectors or l tunable prefix
따라서 접두사 조정을 수행하려면 조정 가능한 접두사 벡터를 준비하거나 조정 가능한 접두사를 l개 준비합니다.
vectors to the keys and values of the multi-head attention at every layer
모든 레이어에서 다중 헤드 어텐션의 키와 값에 대한 벡터
more formally mathematically given a query vector x and a sequence of m vectors c over
보다 공식적으로 수학적으로 쿼리 벡터 x와 m개의 벡터 시퀀스 c가 주어지면
which we would like to perform attention normally multi-head attention takes this form
일반적으로 Attention을 수행하고 싶은 다중 헤드 Attention은 다음과 같은 형식을 취합니다.
where we have the queries keys and values where we take the relevant vector and we map it
관련 벡터를 가져와 매핑하는 쿼리 키와 값이 있는 곳
to queries keys and values through these weight matrices
이러한 가중치 행렬을 통해 키와 값을 쿼리합니다.
but now multi-head attention with prefixes looks like this where now the keys is actually
하지만 이제 접두사가 있는 다중 헤드 주의는 이제 키가 실제로 다음과 같이 보입니다.
the concatenation of the keys as they were before but also now these prefixed keys
이전과 마찬가지로 키를 연결하지만 이제는 접두사가 붙은 키도 연결합니다.
and same with the values so the concatenation of the values as they were before
값과 동일하므로 이전과 마찬가지로 값을 연결합니다.
but now with the prefix values the two sets of our prefix vectors p sub k and p sub v are
그러나 이제 접두사 값을 사용하면 접두사 벡터 p sub k 및 p sub v의 두 세트는 다음과 같습니다.
concatenated with the original keys and values at every attention head and every layer and now
모든 주의 헤드와 모든 레이어에서 원래 키 및 값과 연결되어 있으며 이제
we just have to learn p sub k and p sub v instead of all of the model parameters
우리는 모든 모델 매개변수 대신 p sub k와 p sub v를 학습하면 됩니다.
now i get into prompt tuning which is a descendant of prefix tuning so where in prefix tuning we
이제 접두사 튜닝의 후손인 프롬프트 튜닝에 들어갑니다. 접두사 튜닝에서 우리는
were prefixing activations propended to the keys and values in each layer in each attention head
각 어텐션 헤드의 각 레이어에 있는 키와 값에 붙은 활성화 앞에 접두사를 붙였습니다.
in prompt tuning we prefix key tokens k tokens to the input text and then we just learned the
프롬프트 조정에서는 키 토큰 k 토큰을 입력 텍스트에 접두사로 붙인 다음 방금 배웠습니다.
token embeddings i'm assuming we're all familiar with attention tokenization but here is an example
토큰 임베딩 우리 모두가 어텐션 토큰화에 익숙하다고 가정하지만 여기에 예가 있습니다.
where we have this as an input text it gets broken down into these tokens start of sequence tokens
이것을 입력 텍스트로 가지고 있는 곳에서는 다음 토큰으로 분류됩니다. 시퀀스 토큰의 시작
cls and then basically the words become tokens although there's also subword tokenization that
cls를 사용하면 기본적으로 단어가 토큰이 됩니다. 하위 단어 토큰화도 있지만
isn't shown here but basically these tokens then get mapped to token IDs which then get mapped to
여기에는 표시되지 않지만 기본적으로 이러한 토큰은 토큰 ID에 매핑되고 다음으로 매핑됩니다.
embeddings through an embedding layer but in the case of the prefixed tokens they don't really
임베딩 레이어를 통한 임베딩이지만 접두사가 붙은 토큰의 경우 실제로는 그렇지 않습니다.
correspond to tokens in the vocabulary they just have some associated embeddings that we then learn
어휘의 토큰에 해당하며 우리가 학습하는 관련 임베딩이 있습니다.
in prompt tuning how are these methods evaluated well they're evaluated using the t5 lm adapt model
신속한 조정에서 이러한 방법은 어떻게 잘 평가됩니까? t5 lm 적응 모델을 사용하여 평가됩니다.
of all sizes so there's sort of a a scale shown there right where we have the small models
모든 크기가 있으므로 작은 모델이 있는 곳에 일종의 규모가 표시됩니다.
that have about 60 million parameters and the xxl model and the higher range has 11 billion
약 6천만 개의 매개변수가 있고 xxl 모델과 더 높은 범위에는 110억 개의 매개변수가 있습니다.
parameters and the models are evaluated using the superglue benchmark which is a collection
매개변수와 모델은 컬렉션인 superglue 벤치마크를 사용하여 평가됩니다.
of eight challenging english language understanding tasks for example one of which is boolq which is
8가지 도전적인 영어 이해 과제 중 하나는 boolq입니다.
a question answering dataset involving i believe boolean answers so the first question that they
부울 답변을 믿는 것과 관련된 질문 응답 데이터 세트이므로 첫 번째 질문은
try to answer in this paper is how should the prompt be initialized and three different alternatives
이 문서에서 대답하려고 하는 것은 프롬프트를 어떻게 초기화해야 하는지와 세 가지 다른 대안이 있다는 것입니다.
are considered one is that the prompt is initialized randomly so each number in the embedding is
그 중 하나는 프롬프트가 무작위로 초기화되어 임베딩의 각 숫자가 다음과 같다는 것입니다.
a random number or perhaps prompts can be randomly sampled from the model vocabulary or from the
임의의 숫자나 프롬프트는 모델 어휘나 모델 어휘에서 무작위로 샘플링될 수 있습니다.
5000 most common tokens in the vocabulary we choose random tokens maybe dog sky and purple
어휘에서 가장 일반적인 5000개의 토큰을 무작위로 선택합니다. 어쩌면 개 하늘색과 보라색일 수도 있습니다.
which all form their own tokens and we just take the embeddings of those random tokens initialize
모두 자체 토큰을 형성하고 해당 무작위 토큰의 임베딩을 사용하여 초기화합니다.
using those and then we learn from there alternatively embeddings can also be those that enumerate
이를 사용하여 우리는 거기에서 대안으로 임베딩이 열거되는 것일 수도 있음을 배웁니다.
output classes so if i'm trying to learn a news classification task where i have a passage and
출력 클래스 그래서 내가 구절이 있는 뉴스 분류 작업을 배우려고 한다면
i'm trying to classify it as news related to the world the news related to sports or business news
세상과 관련된 뉴스, 스포츠 관련 뉴스, 비즈니스 뉴스로 분류하려고 합니다.
then i can just take those output classes find the relevant token embeddings and initialize
그런 다음 해당 출력 클래스를 사용하여 관련 토큰 임베딩을 찾고 초기화하면 됩니다.
using those and then we learn our embeddings from there right and just as a reminder prompts are
이를 사용하여 알림 메시지와 마찬가지로 거기에서 임베딩을 학습합니다.
represented as a parameter p sub e that are matrices of size p times e where e is the dimension
크기가 p 곱하기 e인 행렬인 매개변수 p sub e로 표시됩니다. 여기서 e는 차원입니다.
of the embedding space and p is the length of the prompt right and what they find is that while
임베딩 공간의 길이이고 p는 프롬프트 오른쪽의 길이이며 그들이 찾은 것은
they say that class label initialization performs best and they also say that at smaller model sizes
그들은 클래스 레이블 초기화가 가장 잘 수행된다고 말하며 또한 더 작은 모델 크기에서도 그렇게 말합니다.
there are large gaps between the different initializations but once the model is scaled up to
서로 다른 초기화 사이에는 큰 간격이 있지만 일단 모델이 확장되면
the xxl size these differences disappear but i wanted to ask does the chart suggest the same
xxl 사이즈를 사용하면 이러한 차이가 사라지지만 차트에 동일한 내용이 나와 있는지 묻고 싶었습니다.
and so here we have a chart where the x axis is model parameters and the y axis is the average
여기에 x축이 모델 매개변수이고 y축이 평균인 차트가 있습니다.
superglue score and then we have the three methods random uniform sample vocabulary and class label
superglue 점수를 얻은 다음 세 가지 방법으로 무작위로 균일한 샘플 어휘와 클래스 레이블을 얻습니다.
and it's first to say class label initialization performs best but i think the chart suggests
그리고 클래스 라벨 초기화가 가장 잘 수행된다고 말하는 것이 먼저지만 차트에서는 다음과 같이 제안한다고 생각합니다.
that basically class label initialization and sample vocabulary perform very similarly and they
기본적으로 클래스 레이블 초기화와 샘플 어휘는 매우 유사하게 수행되며
walk hand in hand and then for random uniform they say that smaller model sizes there's larger
손을 잡고 걷고 무작위 유니폼의 경우 모델 크기가 작을수록 더 크다고 말합니다.
gaps but once we grow the model the gap shorten and certainly at the largest model all three methods
격차가 있지만 일단 모델을 성장시키면 격차가 줄어들고 확실히 가장 큰 모델에서는 세 가지 방법 모두
perform very similarly but also in the smallest model they perform similarly i think the random
매우 유사하게 수행되지만 가장 작은 모델에서도 유사하게 수행됩니다.
uniform just has more noise and is a method with more variance second question they attempt to
유니폼은 노이즈가 더 많고 두 번째 질문에 더 많은 분산이 있는 방법입니다.
answer is how long should prompts be and they find that across all models increasing beyond
대답은 프롬프트가 얼마나 길어야 하는지이며 모든 모델에서 그 이상으로 증가한다는 것을 발견했습니다.
20 tokens only yields marginal gains and in fact with xxl model it still gives strong results with
20개의 토큰은 미미한 이익만 얻을 수 있으며 실제로 xxl 모델을 사용하면 여전히 강력한 결과를 얻을 수 있습니다.
a single token prompt suggesting that for larger models prompts don't need to be as large and
더 큰 모델의 경우 프롬프트가 그렇게 클 필요가 없음을 제안하는 단일 토큰 프롬프트
not as many parameters need to be learned right actually what's interesting is that in the case
실제로 흥미로운 점은 많은 매개변수를 학습할 필요가 없다는 것입니다.
of the t5 xxl model a single token embedding has dimension 1024 so we're only learning 1024 parameters
t5 xxl 모델의 단일 토큰 임베딩에는 차원이 1024이므로 1024개의 매개변수만 학습합니다.
and that seems to work well so that is quite interesting
그리고 그것은 잘 작동하는 것 같아서 꽤 흥미롭습니다.
and now comparing to other methods interestingly the paper doesn't make effectiveness comparisons
흥미롭게도 다른 방법과 비교하면 논문에서는 효율성을 비교하지 않습니다.
with other path methods only comparisons to full model fine tuning are made for effectiveness
다른 경로 방법의 경우 효율성을 위해 전체 모델 미세 조정과의 비교만 수행됩니다.
they do compare parameter usage with other methods right and they argue that prompt tuning is the most
그들은 매개변수 사용을 다른 방법과 비교하고 있으며 신속한 조정이 가장 중요하다고 주장합니다.
parameter efficient method because it learns very few parameters across the range of model sizes
모델 크기 범위 전체에서 매우 적은 수의 매개변수를 학습하므로 매개변수 효율적인 방법입니다.
but it is interesting that they did not make comparisons with other path methods for effectiveness
그러나 효율성에 대해 다른 경로 방법과 비교하지 않았다는 점이 흥미롭습니다.
on one hand making these comparisons would have required them to reproduce these other
한편으로 이러한 비교를 하려면 다른 한편으로는 이러한 비교를 재현해야 했을 것입니다.
methods which would have been more work but on the other hand i argue that their work on a pep
더 많은 작업이 필요한 방법이지만 반면에 나는 그들의 작업이 격려에 있다고 주장합니다.
method is incomplete without effectiveness comparisons to other path methods
다른 경로 방법과의 효율성 비교가 없으면 방법이 불완전합니다.
they do make comparisons again to full model fine tuning and so we show this right where
그들은 전체 모델의 미세 조정과 다시 비교하므로 우리는 이를 바로 보여줍니다.
prompt tuning becomes more effective with scale they show prompt tuning matches even the stronger
프롬프트 튜닝은 규모가 커질수록 더 효과적입니다. 더 강할수록 프롬프트 튜닝 일치를 보여줍니다.
multi-task model tuning baseline and that is a baseline where a single model is tuned on all
다중 작업 모델 튜닝 기준은 단일 모델이 모든 작업에 대해 튜닝되는 기준입니다.
the superglue tasks at the same time and so that's the strongest baseline and achieves the strongest
동시에 초강력 접착제 작업을 수행하므로 이것이 가장 강력한 기준이 되고 가장 강력한 결과를 얻습니다.
results but for a sufficiently large and up t5 model prompt tuning does just as well as full
결과는 충분하지만 t5 모델 이상의 경우 프롬프트 튜닝이 전체 성능과 동일하게 수행됩니다.
model fine tuning or multi-task full model fine tuning the fourth line there is prompt design the
모델 미세 조정 또는 다중 작업 전체 모델 미세 조정 네 번째 라인이 있어 신속한 설계가 가능합니다.
blue line and that measures the performance of gpt3 in a few shot in context learning example
파란색 선은 상황 학습 예시의 몇 장면에서 gpt3의 성능을 측정합니다.
so their method where they train actually does better than gpt3 just using the t5 model
그래서 그들이 훈련하는 방법은 실제로 t5 모델을 사용하는 gpt3보다 더 낫습니다.
and so the final part of this paper that i'll look at is resilience to domain shift and domain
그래서 제가 살펴볼 이 문서의 마지막 부분은 도메인 이동과 도메인에 대한 탄력성입니다.
shift is the change in data characteristics across context perhaps you train in one context
변화는 상황에 따른 데이터 특성의 변화입니다. 아마도 하나의 상황에서 훈련했을 것입니다.
and then you try to evaluate the model in another context in this example the model is trained on
그런 다음 모델이 훈련된 이 예에서는 다른 맥락에서 모델을 평가하려고 합니다.
the stanford question answering data set and it's evaluated on these other data sets so out of
스탠포드 질문 답변 데이터 세트는 다른 데이터 세트에 대해 평가됩니다.
distribution right so the stanford question answering data set has passages from wikipedia
배포 권한이 있으므로 스탠포드 질문 답변 데이터 세트에는 위키피디아의 구절이 있습니다.
and then we try to answer questions given those passages but the textbook qa data set actually
그런 다음 해당 구절이 주어진 질문에 답하려고 시도하지만 실제로 교과서의 QA 데이터 세트는
has passages from i think a middle school level textbook the questions are also the middle school
중학교 수준 교과서의 구절이 있는 것 같아요. 질문도 중학교 수준인 것 같아요
level knowledge questions and bio ask i believe is a biomedical question answering data set where
레벨 지식 질문과 바이오 질문은 데이터 세트에 응답하는 생물 의학 질문이라고 생각합니다.
the domain is biomedical papers i believe right and so we see that the prompt tuning math that
도메인은 제가 옳다고 생각하는 생의학 논문이므로 즉각적인 튜닝 수학이 가능하다는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
actually does very well in these settings compared to full model fine tuning but again in this table
실제로 전체 모델 미세 조정에 비해 이러한 설정에서 매우 잘 수행되지만 이 표에서는 다시 한 번 언급합니다.
there are there are methods where full model fine tuning does better but anyway the authors argue
전체 모델 미세 조정이 더 나은 방법이 있지만 어쨌든 저자는 주장합니다.
that by freezing the core language model parameters prompt tuning prevents the model from modifying
핵심 언어 모델 매개변수를 동결함으로써 신속한 조정으로 인해 모델이 수정되는 것을 방지할 수 있습니다.
its general understanding of language and this reduces the model's ability to overfit to a data
언어에 대한 일반적인 이해로 인해 모델이 데이터에 과적합되는 능력이 감소합니다.
set which would be bad and that's not something that we want so they argue that prompt tuning may
나쁜 설정이고 우리가 원하는 것이 아니기 때문에 그들은 즉각적인 조정이 필요할 수 있다고 주장합니다.
improve robustness to domain shifts but i present this table as it is and so you might disagree with
도메인 이동에 대한 견고성을 향상하지만 이 표를 있는 그대로 제시하므로 동의하지 않을 수도 있습니다.
that if the results aren't you know a clear prompt tuning looks better
결과가 확실하지 않으면 명확한 프롬프트 튜닝이 더 좋아 보입니다.
i'll now move on to the second paper entitled view shot parameter efficient fine tuning is
이제 뷰 샷 매개변수 효율적인 미세 조정이라는 제목의 두 번째 논문으로 넘어가겠습니다.
better and cheaper than in context learning where they introduce a new path method iacubed
새로운 경로 방법 iacubed를 도입하는 상황 학습보다 더 좋고 저렴합니다.
that comes from this name and the idea of the method is that they learn l sub k l sub v and l
이는 이 이름에서 유래되었으며 이 방법의 아이디어는 그들이 l sub kl sub v 및 l을 학습한다는 것입니다.
sub ff which are vectors with the task of rescaling via l and y's multiplication the keys and the
l과 y의 곱셈을 통해 키와 키를 다시 스케일링하는 작업을 수행하는 벡터인 sub ff
values and attention and the interactivations in feedforward neural networks or in the network
피드포워드 신경망이나 네트워크에서의 가치와 관심, 상호작용
right so here we have the attention mechanism and the values are rescaled using lv the key
여기 주의 메커니즘이 있고 값은 lv 키를 사용하여 재조정됩니다.
is a rescale using lk and then in the feedforward network after the dense layer and the non-linearity
lk를 사용하여 재조정한 다음 조밀한 레이어와 비선형성 이후의 피드포워드 네트워크에서
there is l sub ff which rescales whatever is output from there that's going into the next dense layer
다음 조밀한 레이어로 들어가는 출력의 크기를 조정하는 l sub ff가 있습니다.
so again this paper introduces this method and it argues that peft is better than icl in
그래서 다시 이 문서에서는 이 방법을 소개하고 pft가 icl보다 낫다고 주장합니다.
few shot settings and just to remind you few shot learning is learning from only a few examples
몇 가지 샷 설정과 몇 가지 샷 학습은 몇 가지 예에서만 학습한다는 점을 상기시켜 드립니다.
and icl is in context learning where we induce a model to perform a downstream task about inputting
icl은 입력에 대한 다운스트림 작업을 수행하도록 모델을 유도하는 컨텍스트 학습에 있습니다.
prompted examples and so here's an example of both few shot and icl so it's a four shot input
프롬프트된 예이므로 여기에 몇 개의 샷과 icl의 예가 있으므로 4개의 샷 입력이 됩니다.
for context that is please unscramble the letters into a word so we're asking the model to unscramble
문맥상 문자를 단어로 풀어서 모델에 풀어달라고 요청합니다.
these letters and write the word and so here are four examples for example asinoc gets
이 문자를 입력하고 단어를 쓰세요. 예를 들어 asinoc이 얻는 네 가지 예는 다음과 같습니다.
re scrambled to casino and so we wanted to unscramble that last example astedro and it would
카지노로 다시 출격해서 우리는 마지막 예인 astedro를 풀어보고 싶었습니다.
hopefully rescramble that to roasted now what's wrong with in context learning well the advantage
이제 상황에 맞게 이점을 잘 익히면서 문제가 무엇인지 다시 확인하시기 바랍니다.
the author say is that icl they recognize does enable single models to perform many tasks without
저자는 icl이 단일 모델이 별도의 작업 없이 많은 작업을 수행할 수 있게 해준다고 말합니다.
fine-tuning but the disadvantage is that making predictions is expensive because the model needs
하지만 단점은 모델이 필요하기 때문에 예측하는 데 비용이 많이 든다는 것입니다.
to process all the in-context examples every single time a prediction is made
예측이 이루어질 때마다 모든 상황 내 예시를 처리합니다.
so instead of in context learning peft is a promising alternative
따라서 상황에 맞게 학습하는 대신 peft가 유망한 대안입니다.
so how they evaluate their methods is they use the t0 model which is created by fine-tuning
그래서 그들이 방법을 평가하는 방법은 미세 조정을 통해 생성된 t0 모델을 사용하는 것입니다.
the t5 model in a mixture of datasets to enable zero shot generalization for each dataset that
각 데이터세트에 대해 제로샷 일반화를 가능하게 하기 위해 데이터세트를 혼합한 t5 모델
they test the number of few shot examples used varies from 20 to 70 and that's not arbitrary
그들은 사용된 몇 가지 샷 예제의 수를 20에서 70까지 다양하게 테스트하며 이는 임의적이지 않습니다.
they do that to match the same number as the evaluation from the paper language models or
종이 언어 모델의 평가와 동일한 숫자를 일치시키기 위해 그렇게 합니다.
few shot learners and that's a paper that looks at few shot learning with the gp3 model and that's
소수의 샷 학습자 그리고 그것은 gp3 모델을 사용한 소수의 샷 학습을 살펴보는 논문입니다.
a paper by openai and so the datasets they consider stretch you know these four different
openai의 논문과 그들이 고려하는 데이터 세트는 다음 네 가지가 있다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
areas sentence completion natural language inference coreference resolution and word
영역 문장 완성 자연어 추론 상호 참조 해결 및 단어
sense disambiguation very quickly sentence completion is you know given one sentence you
명확성을 매우 빠르게 감지 문장 완성 당신은 한 문장이 주어진 것을 알고 있습니까?
just complete it natural language inference is given some premise we classify whether or not
그냥 완료하세요 자연어 추론에는 전제가 주어집니다.
another premise is logically entailed by that first sentence or by the first premise if we say
또 다른 전제는 첫 번째 문장이나 첫 번째 전제에 논리적으로 수반됩니다.
you know dot dot dot she was playing golf with Ron when her phone rang and it was Liz her mother's
너도 알잖아, 도트 도트 도트 그녀가 Ron과 골프를 치고 있을 때 그녀의 전화가 울렸는데 그것은 Liz의 어머니 전화였어
friend if we say that Liz called Taylor that is logically entailed if we say Ron called Taylor
친구, Liz가 Taylor에게 전화했다고 말하면 Ron이 Taylor에게 전화했다고 말하면 논리적으로 수반됩니다.
that's a contradiction that doesn't make sense and if we say a doctor called Taylor
그건 말도 안 되는 모순인데, 테일러라는 의사를 말한다면
perhaps Liz is a doctor so that's unknown logically coreference resolution is recognizing
아마도 리즈는 의사이기 때문에 논리적으로 상호 참조 해결이 인식되는지 알 수 없습니다.
whether or not an entity is referring to the same thing as another entity in some text and word
엔터티가 일부 텍스트 및 단어에서 다른 엔터티와 동일한 것을 참조하는지 여부
sense disambiguation is figuring out in what sense do we mean of the word if we say something we
의미 명확성은 우리가 뭔가를 말할 때 그 단어가 어떤 의미로 의미되는지 알아내는 것입니다.
please open the window to let some fresh air in are we referring to you know the kind of
창문을 열어서 신선한 공기가 들어오게 해주세요. 어떤 종류인지 아시나요?
window that we look out of to see outside or are we talking about the operating system
우리가 밖을 보기 위해 내다보는 창, 아니면 운영체제에 대해 이야기하는 걸까요?
and so here are the results they compare iac cubed both with other path methods and they compare
그래서 여기에 그들이 iac 세제곱을 다른 경로 방법과 비교한 결과가 있습니다.
iac cubed in the tfue model with icl and so it's actually pretty confusing so the number
iac는 icl을 사용하여 tfue 모델에서 세제곱되므로 실제로는 꽤 혼란스럽습니다.
of things i need to explain first of all the comparison with peft methods is made with a
먼저 설명해야 할 것 중 하나는 peft 방법과의 비교입니다.
three billion parameter version of the model and the comparisons with icl is made with 11
모델의 30억 매개변수 버전과 icl과의 비교는 11로 이루어졌습니다.
billion parameter version of the model they say it's just quicker to evaluate with three billion
30억으로 평가하는 것이 더 빠르다고 말하는 모델의 10억 매개변수 버전
parameter models because it's just smaller and easier to work with
매개변수 모델은 더 작고 작업하기 쉽기 때문에
so starting with the left figure we see that iac cubed actually does very well it beats full
따라서 왼쪽 그림부터 시작하면 iac Cubed가 실제로 아주 잘 작동한다는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
model fine-tuning which is marked by the dash line and it beats the other methods
점선으로 표시된 모델 미세 조정은 다른 방법보다 우수합니다.
some of these which we have covered like adapters prompt tuning prefix tuning and laura
어댑터 프롬프트 튜닝 접두사 튜닝 및 Laura와 같이 우리가 다룬 이들 중 일부
and it does so with not a large amount of parameters updated a relatively modest amount
상대적으로 적당한 양으로 업데이트된 매개변수의 양이 많지 않은 경우에도 마찬가지입니다.
so now comparing to icl these baselines are not intuitive so let's explain tfue is just
이제 icl과 비교하면 이러한 기준선은 직관적이지 않으므로 tfue는 단지
taking a t0 fine-tuning it with iac cubed and then evaluating that and that performs the best
T0를 iac 입방체로 미세 조정한 다음 이를 평가하면 가장 좋은 성능을 발휘합니다.
in terms of accuracy and x-axis is number of flops for example so the amount of floating
정확도 측면에서 x축은 플롭 수입니다. 예를 들어 플로팅 양은
point operation is needed to make a prediction right so t0 evaluates the t0 11 billion parameter
예측을 올바르게 하려면 포인트 연산이 필요하므로 t0은 t0 110억 매개변수를 평가합니다.
model in a zero shot setting so without any training or without even in-contact learning
제로샷 설정에서 모델을 구축하므로 교육이나 대면 학습 없이도 가능합니다.
and that actually does fairly well it does better than gpt3 in the in-contact learning setting so
그리고 그것은 실제로 상당히 잘 수행됩니다. 접촉 학습 설정에서는 gpt3보다 더 낫습니다.
that's a relevant baseline to include the t5 plus lm actually evaluates the t5 lm adapt 11
이는 t5 plus lm을 포함하는 관련 기준입니다. 실제로 t5 lmadapt 11을 평가합니다.
billion parameter model with ensemble icl so it's using icl and because the context window
앙상블 icl이 포함된 10억 매개변수 모델이므로 icl을 사용하고 있으며 컨텍스트 창이
of the t5 is so small each example in is basically its own context and then the predictions are
t5의 각 예는 기본적으로 자체 컨텍스트이고 예측은 너무 작습니다.
averaged so if i have four examples there are four predictions made using the t5 model and
평균이므로 4개의 예가 있으면 t5 모델을 사용하여 4개의 예측이 이루어지고
those predictions are averaged and they don't do icl with the t0 model because they show that
이러한 예측은 평균화되었으며 다음을 보여주기 때문에 t0 모델로 icl을 수행하지 않습니다.
actually the results were worse than not using icl so the baseline model for icl for the t5
실제로 결과는 icl을 사용하지 않는 것보다 나빴으므로 t5에 대한 icl의 기본 모델은
model is this which actually performs the worst of all the methods in that in that figure and then
모델은 실제로 해당 그림에 있는 모든 방법 중 최악의 방법을 수행하는 것입니다.
there's the gpt3 which is the strong icl baseline which performs relatively well but it takes a lot
비교적 잘 수행되는 강력한 icl 기준인 gpt3가 있지만 시간이 많이 걸립니다.
of floating point operations to compute and in fact it still doesn't do as well as tfue
계산할 부동 소수점 연산이 있지만 실제로는 여전히 tfue만큼 잘 수행되지 않습니다.
right so now making arguments about efficiency the tfue method shines in terms of inference
그래서 지금은 효율성에 대한 논쟁을 벌이고 있는데 tfue 방법은 추론 측면에서 빛을 발합니다.
floating point operations it is very cheap to make a prediction compared to the other methods
부동 소수점 연산은 다른 방법에 비해 예측하는 것이 매우 저렴합니다.
especially the icl methods right that being said it is a model that is trained unlike the other
특히 icl 방법은 다른 모델과 달리 훈련된 모델이라고 합니다.
methods and so there is a cost to that so the flops again are the floating point operations to
메서드를 사용하므로 비용이 발생하므로 플롭은 다시 부동 소수점 연산입니다.
make a prediction for a single example and so again tfue method performs the best it has low
단일 예에 대해 예측을 하고 다시 tfue 방법이 낮은 수준에서 최선을 다합니다.
inference floating point operations but it does take some cost to train and the disk space is not
부동 소수점 연산을 추론하지만 훈련하는 데 약간의 비용이 들고 디스크 공간이 충분하지 않습니다.
too interesting but basically the parameters of the model need to be stored and so the extra cost
너무 흥미롭지만 기본적으로 모델의 매개변수를 저장해야 하므로 추가 비용이 발생합니다.
of storing those models is you know a disk space usage of four megabytes which is basically nothing
해당 모델을 저장하려면 기본적으로 아무 것도 아닌 4MB의 디스크 공간 사용량을 알고 있어야 합니다.
because these models and their weights already take you know gigabytes to store the 11 billion
왜냐하면 이 모델과 그 무게는 이미 110억 개의 데이터를 저장하는 데 기가바이트가 걸리기 때문입니다.
parameter model i think it's probably like 30 gigabytes to store and the gpt3 models at 170
매개변수 모델은 저장 공간이 30GB 정도이고 gpt3 모델은 170 정도인 것 같아요.
billion parameters will be a lot to store but that four megabytes is the cost of storing the
10억 개의 매개변수를 저장하려면 많은 양이 필요하지만 4MB는
additional parameters and the 16 kilobytes is the cost of storing the input prompt for each task
추가 매개변수이며 16킬로바이트는 각 작업에 대한 입력 프롬프트를 저장하는 데 드는 비용입니다.
16 kilobytes is basically nothing right now that's some criticism of this work that i wanted to share
16킬로바이트는 기본적으로 지금은 아무것도 아닙니다. 이 작업에 대한 비판을 공유하고 싶었습니다.
one is that the experiments were on classification tasks only optimally i'd like to see
하나는 실험이 내가 보고 싶은 최적의 분류 작업에 대해서만 수행되었다는 것입니다.
experiments done on other tasks for example generative question answering
생성적 질문 답변과 같은 다른 작업에 대한 실험
other criticism is that the valuation was only done using the t0 model
다른 비판은 가치 평가가 t0 모델을 사용하여 수행되었다는 것입니다.
optimally as a parameter efficient fine tuning method it should be evaluated in other models
최적의 매개변수 효율적인 미세 조정 방법으로서 다른 모델에서 평가되어야 합니다.
models as well the t0 model is an encoder decoder model maybe some experiment should be done with
모델 역시 t0 모델은 인코더 디코더 모델일 수 있습니다. 아마도 몇 가지 실험을 수행해야 할 것입니다.
encoder only models like the burp family of models where decoder only models like a lot of the open
디코더 전용 모델이 많은 개방형 모델인 Burp 모델 제품군과 같은 인코더 전용 모델
lm's that we're seeing today llama or mistral
오늘 우리가 보는 것은 라마나 미스트랄이에요
final criticism is that the valuation of the peft method is only done in the few shot setting
마지막 비판은 페프트 방식의 평가가 소수샷 설정에서만 이루어진다는 것이다.
and that is the point of the paper i recognize that but i would have liked to see the evaluation
그리고 그것이 내가 알고 있는 논문의 요점이지만 평가를 보고 싶었습니다.
of this method in a more high resource setting where a lot of training data is made available
많은 교육 데이터를 사용할 수 있는 보다 높은 리소스 설정에서 이 방법을 사용합니다.
and now i that brings me to this paper that is towards a unified view of parameter efficient
이제 매개변수 효율성에 대한 통합된 관점을 지향하는 이 문서로 이동했습니다.
transfer learning which relates prefix tuning to adapters and then tries to draw new insights from
접두사 조정을 어댑터와 연관시킨 다음 어댑터에서 새로운 통찰력을 얻으려고 시도하는 전이 학습
that relation mainly they try to answer so as i just mentioned can adapters lower on prefix
그 관계는 주로 내가 방금 언급한 것처럼 어댑터의 접두사를 낮출 수 있도록 대답하려고 합니다.
tuning be related to one another and in fact they can and a unified understanding of these
튜닝은 서로 관련되어 있으며 실제로 이러한 튜닝에 대한 통일된 이해가 가능합니다.
allow for the creation of even better even better parameter efficient fine tuning methods
훨씬 더 나은 매개변수 효율적인 미세 조정 방법을 생성할 수 있습니다.
we call adapters uh we've already covered this but basically the adapter approaches
우리는 어댑터라고 부릅니다. 어 우리는 이미 이것을 다뤘지만 기본적으로 어댑터는
approach inserts small modules between transform layers and so there's a down projection matrix
접근 방식은 변환 레이어 사이에 작은 모듈을 삽입하므로 하향 투영 행렬이 있습니다.
and up projection matrix and a normal linear activation function you know go very quickly
투영 행렬과 일반적인 선형 활성화 함수는 매우 빠르게 진행됩니다.
over this but basically we can derive a new functional form uh of what the adapter is doing
하지만 기본적으로 어댑터가 수행하는 작업에 대한 새로운 기능적 형식을 파생할 수 있습니다.
where the new hidden states equals the old hidden states plus uh the output of the adapter which is
여기서 새로운 숨겨진 상태는 이전 숨겨진 상태에 어댑터의 출력을 더한 것과 같습니다.
the activation the old hidden state times the down projection and then all that matrix multiply
이전 은닉 상태 활성화에 하향 투영을 곱한 다음 모든 행렬을 곱합니다.
with up projection so let's remember this for later now let's try to derive a similar functional
상향 투영을 사용하므로 나중에 이것을 기억해 두겠습니다. 비슷한 함수를 파생해 보겠습니다.
form for prefix tuning so to do prefix tuning again we talked about this but to recall two sets
접두사 튜닝을 위한 양식이므로 다시 접두사 튜닝을 수행하기 위해 이에 대해 이야기했지만 두 세트를 기억해 보겠습니다.
of prefix vectors are concatenated with the original keys and values at every attention
의 접두사 벡터는 모든 주의에서 원래 키 및 값과 연결됩니다.
head in every layer and then given a query of vector x and a sequence of m vector c over which
모든 레이어의 머리에 벡터 x와 m개의 벡터 c 시퀀스에 대한 쿼리가 제공됩니다.
we would like to perform attention um that prefix tuning takes them this form right
우리는 접두사 튜닝이 이러한 형식을 올바르게 취한다는 점에 주목하고 싶습니다.
we have the queries the keys which is a concatenation of pk and the keys as they would have been
우리는 pk와 키를 연결한 키에 대한 쿼리를 가지고 있습니다.
otherwise and the values which is the concatenation of pv and the values as they would have been
그렇지 않으면 pv와 값을 연결한 값입니다.
otherwise without prefix tuning now this statement can actually be rewritten as this and I've skipped
그렇지 않으면 접두사 조정 없이 이제 이 명령문은 실제로 다음과 같이 다시 작성될 수 있으며 건너뛰었습니다.
a few steps but uh basically it takes on this form where lambda x is a scalar that represents the
몇 단계만 거치면 되지만 어 기본적으로 람다 x가 다음을 나타내는 스칼라인 이 형식을 취합니다.
sum of normalized attention weights on the prefixes and in this formula i and j index values in the
접두사에 대한 정규화된 주의 가중치의 합과 이 공식에서 i 및 j 인덱스 값
vector basically lambda x is a scalar and we rewritten prefix tuning as this form where
벡터는 기본적으로 람다 x는 스칼라이며 접두사 조정을 다음 형식으로 다시 작성했습니다.
as attention was for just on this form right with the queries keys and values with prefix
접두사가 있는 쿼리 키와 값이 있는 이 양식에만 관심이 있었기 때문에
tuning we've separated it out into as it is normally attention but also uh the add the added
튜닝은 일반적으로 주의 사항이므로 분리했지만 어 추가 사항도 추가되었습니다.
modification with prefix tuning so alternative view of the prefix tuning in the functional
접두사 조정을 통한 수정으로 기능적 측면에서 접두사 조정에 대한 대체 보기
form we've been considering is of this form right h takes on one minus lambda x h as it was before
우리가 생각해 왔던 형태는 이런 형태입니다. 맞습니다. h는 이전과 마찬가지로 1 - 람다 xh를 취합니다.
plus lambda x time is the modification to h where and delta h is a modification to the original
플러스 람다 x 시간은 h에 대한 수정이고, 델타 h는 원본에 대한 수정입니다.
head attention output h through linear interpolation and it's linear interpolation because of these
머리 주의 출력 h는 선형 보간을 통해 이루어지며 이로 인해 선형 보간이 됩니다.
scalars one minus lambda x and lambda x
스칼라 1 - 람다 x 및 람다 x
so now we're relating prefix tuning in adapters again we have this function of form for prefix
이제 다시 어댑터의 접두사 조정과 관련하여 접두사에 대한 형식의 기능이 있습니다.
tuning and we have this functional form for adapters now if we define w sub one as this
조정하고 w sub one을 다음과 같이 정의하면 이제 어댑터에 대한 기능적 형식이 있습니다.
and w sub two as this and f as softmax function well then we can rewrite what we have
그리고 w sub 2는 이것으로, f는 Softmax 함수로 사용하면 우리가 가지고 있는 것을 다시 작성할 수 있습니다.
have the functional form of prefix tuning to this which looks a lot like adapters except that
이를 제외하고는 어댑터와 매우 유사해 보이는 접두사 조정의 기능적 형태가 있습니다.
prefix tuning is doing weighted addition because of those lambdas
접두사 조정은 람다 때문에 가중치 추가를 수행합니다.
now we have these very sim similar functional forms but there are some key differences
이제 우리는 매우 유사한 기능적 형태를 가지게 되었지만 몇 가지 중요한 차이점이 있습니다.
one is that prefix tuning uses x to compute the change to h while adapters use h to compute
하나는 접두사 조정이 x를 사용하여 h에 대한 변경 사항을 계산하는 반면 어댑터는 h를 사용하여 계산한다는 것입니다.
the change to h and so there's a difference there in parallel versus sequential computation
h로 변경되므로 병렬 계산과 순차 계산에 차이가 있습니다.
and that might be easier to understand if you look at this graphic where in adapters
어댑터에 있는 이 그래픽을 보면 더 쉽게 이해할 수 있습니다.
we first pass the inputs x through the plm module to get h and then that h is taken into the second
먼저 plm 모듈을 통해 입력 x를 전달하여 h를 얻은 다음 해당 h를 두 번째 모듈로 가져옵니다.
you know adapters branch to compute the new h the new hidden state whereas in prefix tuning
접두사 조정에서는 새로운 숨겨진 상태를 계산하는 어댑터 분기를 알고 있습니다.
we don't pass x through the plm module to go into the second branch it actually is passed
실제로 전달되는 두 번째 분기로 이동하기 위해 plm 모듈을 통해 x를 전달하지 않습니다.
right into the second branch so we have basically h as it would have been without prefix tuning and
바로 두 번째 브랜치로 들어가므로 기본적으로 접두사 조정 없이 h를 갖게 됩니다.
h with prefix tuning and then we can add these together right another difference though is
h를 접두사 튜닝으로 추가한 다음 이를 함께 추가할 수 있습니다. 또 다른 차이점은 다음과 같습니다.
that adapters are more flexible with respect to where they're inserted adapters can modify both
어댑터는 삽입 위치와 관련하여 더 유연합니다. 어댑터는 두 가지 모두를 수정할 수 있습니다.
attention but also the feed forward net outputs while prefix tuning only modifies the attention
주의뿐만 아니라 피드 포워드 순 출력도 있지만 접두사 튜닝은 주의만 수정합니다.
output of each head and so you might see that in this transformer block where adapters can be
각 헤드의 출력이므로 이 변압기 블록에서 어댑터가 있는 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
inserted here right after the attention module or adapters can be inserted here right after the
주의 모듈 바로 뒤에 여기에 삽입하거나 어댑터를 주의 모듈 바로 뒤에 여기에 삽입할 수 있습니다.
feed forward network whereas with prefix tuning we see that the p sub k and the p sub b are only
피드 포워드 네트워크인 반면 접두사 튜닝에서는 p sub k와 p sub b만
basically changing things within the attention module
기본적으로 주의 모듈 내에서 내용을 변경합니다.
but now to summarize the differences between prefix tuning adapters and laura which is also
이제 접두사 튜닝 어댑터와 Laura의 차이점을 요약하겠습니다.
similar and relevant uh first let's look at the insertion forms so as we just mentioned adapters
유사하고 관련성이 높습니다. 어 먼저 방금 어댑터에 대해 언급한 것처럼 삽입 양식을 살펴보겠습니다.
are sequential but prefix tuning and even laura is uh parallel and so you might you can see that
순차적이지만 접두사 조정이 가능하고 Laura도 어 병렬이므로 알 수 있을 것입니다.
this graphic for laura as for what representations they modify as we just mentioned adapters can
방금 언급한 것처럼 Laura가 어떤 표현을 수정하는지에 대한 이 그래픽은 어댑터가 할 수 있습니다.
modify both feed forward network part and the attention whereas prefix tuning can only modify
피드 포워드 네트워크 부분과 주의를 모두 수정하는 반면 접두사 튜닝은 수정만 할 수 있습니다.
the head attention and laura can only modify the keys and the values in attention right so laura
머리 주의와 Laura는 주의에 있는 키와 값만 수정할 수 있습니다. 그래서 Laura는
again in the transformer block laura modifies here the weights matrix for queries and the
다시 변환기 블록에서 Laura는 여기서 쿼리에 대한 가중치 행렬을 수정하고
weights matrix for keys and then we have these composition functions which we've been looking
키에 대한 가중치 행렬 그리고 우리가 찾고 있던 이러한 구성 함수가 있습니다.
at uh and there's a new one for laura where basically the composition function for laura
어 그리고 기본적으로 Laura를 위한 구성 기능이 있는 Laura를 위한 새로운 기능이 있습니다.
looks a lot like adapters but there's the addition of this s hyper parameter basically that scales
어댑터와 매우 비슷해 보이지만 기본적으로 확장 가능한 하이퍼 매개변수가 추가되어 있습니다.
the change to h and we have the function forms for delta h here
h에 대한 변경이고 여기에 델타 h에 대한 함수 형식이 있습니다.
now how can these methods be used to formulate new path methods well there are a bunch of different
이제 이러한 방법을 사용하여 새로운 경로 방법을 공식화하는 방법에는 여러 가지가 있습니다.
differences right between these methods so we can test and compare which variant of these
이러한 방법들 사이의 차이점이 있으므로 이들 중 어떤 변형이 있는지 테스트하고 비교할 수 있습니다.
differences forms better so we can compare parallel versus sequential insertion modifying
차이점이 더 잘 형성되므로 병렬 삽입 수정과 순차 삽입 수정을 비교할 수 있습니다.
attention representations versus modifying the feed forward network representations
주의 표현과 피드 포워드 네트워크 표현 수정 비교
and scaling the composition function or leaving unscaled
구성 기능의 크기를 조정하거나 크기를 조정하지 않은 상태로 둡니다.
and so in evaluation these are the data sets they use the x sum data set which is a news
그래서 평가에서 이것은 뉴스인 x 합계 데이터 세트를 사용하는 데이터 세트입니다.
article summarization data set english to romanian translation m and li which is a natural language
기사 요약 데이터 세트 영어에서 루마니아어 번역 m 및 자연어인 li
inference data set in sst2 which is a sentiment classification data set and they evaluate on
감정 분류 데이터 세트인 sst2의 추론 데이터 세트는 다음을 평가합니다.
these data sets using these models the large model which is an encoder-decoder generative model
이러한 모델을 사용하는 데이터 세트는 인코더-디코더 생성 모델인 대규모 모델입니다.
for the summarization and translation tasks and reberda base which is just an encoder model for
요약 및 번역 작업을 위한 인코더 모델인 reberda base
mnli and sst2 tasks which can be shown as just classification tasks
단지 분류 작업으로 표시될 수 있는 mnli 및 sst2 작업
so now the first question is sequential or parallel what is better
이제 첫 번째 질문은 순차 또는 병렬 중 어느 것이 더 낫습니까?
well prefix tuning which uses parallel insertion outperforms sequential attention attention
병렬 삽입을 사용하는 접두사 튜닝은 순차적 주의 주의보다 성능이 뛰어납니다.
sequential adapters so we see that in this table where the parallel adapters basically
순차 어댑터이므로 이 표에서 병렬 어댑터는 기본적으로
do better than the sequential ones and prefix tuning which is a parallel method
순차 튜닝과 병렬 방식인 프리픽스 튜닝보다 성능이 좋습니다.
does better than the sequential adapters as well
순차 어댑터보다 더 나은 성능을 발휘합니다.
uh one thing to note is that the number of parameters change is kept comparable using these
어 한 가지 주목할 점은 매개변수 변경 횟수가 다음을 사용하여 비교 가능하다는 것입니다.
hyperparameters l and r where r is the bottleneck dimension in the case of lora and adapters
하이퍼파라미터 l 및 r 여기서 r은 lora 및 어댑터의 경우 병목 현상 차원입니다.
and l is the length of the prefix in the case of prefix tuning
l은 프리픽스 튜닝의 경우 프리픽스의 길이입니다.
all right so a parallel adapter from this work is able to beat sequential adapters in all cases
좋습니다. 따라서 이 작업의 병렬 어댑터는 모든 경우에 순차 어댑터를 능가할 수 있습니다.
the parallel adapter is something that they introduce here
병렬 어댑터는 여기에서 소개하는 것입니다.
okay and second question then is do we modify attention or feed for networks
좋습니다. 그러면 두 번째 질문은 네트워크에 대한 관심이나 피드를 수정하는 것입니까?
right so some observations is that any method with feed for network
맞습니다. 일부 관찰에 따르면 네트워크 피드를 사용하는 모든 방법은
modification up forms all the methods with attention modification in all cases
수정은 모든 경우에 주의 수정을 통해 모든 방법을 형성합니다.
and so here's this graphic where we have in red the methods that modify the feed for network
여기에 네트워크 피드를 수정하는 방법이 빨간색으로 표시된 그래픽이 있습니다.
and in blue the methods that modify attention including the red methods do better across the
파란색에서는 빨간색 방법을 포함하여 주의를 수정하는 방법이 전체에서 더 나은 성능을 발휘합니다.
number of parameters fine tuned however modifying head attention shows the best results when the
매개변수의 수를 미세 조정했지만 머리 주의를 수정하면 최상의 결과를 얻을 수 있습니다.
parameter budget is very small and so that's shown in this table here where when the number of
매개변수 예산은 매우 작으므로 이 표에 나와 있습니다.
parameters changed as kept very small actually the the method that modifies the attention forms
실제로 주의 형태를 수정하는 방법은 매우 작게 유지되면서 변경된 매개변수입니다.
the best and that's a parallel adapter that modifies attention but also prefix tuning which
최고이며 주의를 수정하는 동시에 접두사 튜닝도 수행하는 병렬 어댑터입니다.
also only modifies attention does better than these other methods a third question to answer
또한 주의력을 수정하는 것은 이러한 다른 방법보다 더 나은 결과를 낳습니다. 세 번째 질문에 대답해 보세요.
which we've covered is should the composition function be scaled or left unscaled and they
우리가 다룬 내용은 구성 함수의 크기를 조정해야 하는지, 크기를 조정하지 않은 상태로 두어야 하는지에 대한 것입니다.
find that the scaling composition function is better than the vanilla additive one you just
스케일링 구성 기능이 방금 바닐라 첨가제 기능보다 낫다는 것을 알았습니다.
have to find the right s value and so in the table here we have laura with s equals four
올바른 s 값을 찾아야 하므로 여기 표에는 s가 4인 Laura가 있습니다.
versus s equals one where one is basically a default and s equals four does better and then
대 s는 1과 같습니다. 여기서 1은 기본적으로 기본값이고 s는 4와 같으며 더 좋습니다.
you have parallel adapters with s equals four doing the best and a trainable s doing not as good as
당신은 s가 4와 같고 훈련 가능한 s가 그만큼 좋지 않은 병렬 어댑터를 가지고 있습니다.
s equals four but still doing better than parallel adapters in the default where s equals one
s는 4와 같지만 기본적으로 s가 1인 병렬 어댑터보다 성능이 더 좋습니다.
right so a learning scalar does not give much better results than manually tuning the scalar
맞습니다. 따라서 학습 스칼라는 스칼라를 수동으로 조정하는 것보다 더 나은 결과를 제공하지 않습니다.
which is interesting but here's where the sort of the unified view comes where
흥미롭지만 여기에 일종의 통합된 보기가 나오는 곳이 있습니다.
the best design elements can be combined to create an even better parameter efficient fine
최고의 디자인 요소를 결합하여 더욱 효율적인 매개변수를 생성할 수 있습니다.
tuning method so they found that the scaled parallel adapter is the best variant to modify
그래서 그들은 확장된 병렬 어댑터가 수정하기에 가장 좋은 변형이라는 것을 발견했습니다.
the feed for network they also found that feed for networks can better utilize modifications at
그들은 네트워크 피드에서 수정 사항을 더 잘 활용할 수 있다는 사실도 발견했습니다.
larger parameter counts however when the parameter budget is small so only when we want to modify
그러나 매개변수 예산이 작은 경우에는 매개변수 수가 더 많아지므로 수정하려는 경우에만 가능합니다.
a small number of parameters that actually modifying head attentions with prefix tuning can
접두어 튜닝으로 머리 주의를 실제로 수정하는 소수의 매개변수는
achieve strong performance right so this paper presents this method the mix and match adapter
강력한 성능을 얻을 수 있으므로 이 문서에서는 믹스 앤 매치 어댑터에 대한 방법을 제시합니다.
that combining all of these findings actually attains strong results and we see that in this
이러한 모든 발견을 결합하면 실제로 강력한 결과를 얻을 수 있다는 점을 알 수 있습니다.
table here where it is compared against both full model fine tuning a lot of the methods that we've
여기 표에서는 우리가 지금까지 수행한 많은 방법을 전체 모델 미세 조정과 비교합니다.
talked about prompt tuning prefix tuning lora parallel adapter which they introduced in this work
이번 작품에서 소개한 프롬프트 튜닝 프리픽스 튜닝 로라 병렬 어댑터에 대해 이야기했습니다.
as well and basically the mix and match adapter which combines a lot of the findings forms the best
그리고 기본적으로 많은 결과를 결합하는 믹스 앤 매치 어댑터가 가장 좋습니다.
although compared to full model fine tuning it's a hit or miss so sometimes it'll do better
전체 모델 미세 조정에 비해 히트 또는 실패이므로 때로는 더 잘할 수 있습니다.
sometimes it'll do worse
가끔은 상황이 더 나빠질 때도 있을 거야
and so that's interesting right and so concluding that last paper moving on
그게 흥미롭군요. 마지막 논문은 다음으로 넘어가겠습니다.
into trying to compare parameter efficient fine tuning and full model fine tuning
매개변수 효율적인 미세 조정과 전체 모델 미세 조정을 비교하려고 합니다.
you know up to this point it looks like full model fine tuning can do better sometimes
당신은 지금까지 전체 모델의 미세 조정이 때로는 더 나은 것처럼 보인다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
parameter efficient fine tuning can do better sometimes with this advantage is so what do you
매개변수 효율적인 미세 조정이 때때로 더 나은 결과를 가져올 수 있다는 이점이 있습니다.
pick right and so they provide a number of relevant observations
올바른 것을 선택하면 관련 관찰이 많이 제공됩니다.
they find that parameter efficient fine tuning methods perform the best and low to medium
그들은 매개변수 효율적인 미세 조정 방법이 가장 좋고 낮거나 중간 정도의 성능을 발휘한다는 것을 발견했습니다.
resource scenarios whereas full model fine tuning does better in high resource scenarios
리소스 시나리오에서는 전체 모델 미세 조정이 리소스가 많은 시나리오에서 더 잘 수행되는 반면
now what does that mean because it is arbitrary so basically to them low resources at most 100
이제 그것은 임의적이므로 기본적으로 최대 100의 리소스가 부족하기 때문에 이것이 무엇을 의미합니까?
data points medium resources at most a thousand data points so ranging from 100 to a thousand
데이터 포인트 중간 리소스 최대 1000개의 데이터 포인트(100~1000개 범위)
in high resource is at most 10 000 realistically anything more than a thousand
높은 자원의 경우 최대 10,000개, 현실적으로는 1,000개 이상
but in their testing it's 1000 to 10 000 right so half methods do better in low resource full
하지만 테스트에서는 1000에서 10,000이 맞으므로 리소스가 부족할 때 절반의 방법이 더 좋습니다.
model fine tuning is better in high resource although looking at the table you know in low
낮은 리소스에서 알고 있는 테이블을 보면 모델 미세 조정이 높은 리소스에서 더 좋습니다.
resource here all the parameter efficient fine tuning methods are leading with medium resource full
여기의 리소스는 모든 매개변수 효율적인 미세 조정 방법이 중간 리소스 가득 참으로 이어지고 있습니다.
model fine tuning actually leads in this data set in the other data sets it's path methods that
모델 미세 조정은 실제로 이 데이터 세트를 다른 데이터 세트로 유도합니다. 이는 경로 방법입니다.
are winning and then in high resource scenarios full model fine tuning does better in two of the
이기고 리소스가 많은 시나리오에서는 전체 모델 미세 조정이 두 가지에서 더 잘 수행됩니다.
data sets but it's still parameter efficient fine tuning methods that do better in the other two
데이터 세트이지만 여전히 다른 두 가지에서 더 나은 성능을 발휘하는 매개변수 효율적인 미세 조정 방법입니다.
now they also show that parameter efficient fine tuning methods are slower to converge in low
이제 그들은 또한 매개변수 효율적인 미세 조정 방법이 낮은 수준에서 수렴하는 속도가 더 느리다는 것을 보여줍니다.
resource scenarios but faster to converge in high resource scenarios so basically their general
리소스 시나리오는 리소스가 많은 시나리오에서 수렴하는 것이 더 빠르므로 기본적으로 일반적입니다.
advice is that if you have a lot of training data the parameter efficient fine tuning method
조언은 훈련 데이터가 많으면 매개변수를 효율적으로 미세 조정하는 방법이라는 것입니다.
will be quicker but it won't perform as well and if you don't have a lot of training data
더 빠르지만 성능이 좋지 않으며 훈련 데이터가 많지 않으면
the parameter efficient fine tuning method will do better but it will be slower to train
매개변수 효율적인 미세 조정 방법은 더 나은 성능을 발휘하지만 훈련 속도는 느려집니다.
which are both considerations if you're training models
모델을 훈련하는 경우 두 가지 모두 고려 사항입니다.
and so in application hugging face peft supports many of the fine tuning methods we discussed on
따라서 응용 프로그램에서 포옹 얼굴 peft는 우리가 논의한 많은 미세 조정 방법을 지원합니다.
modern models out of the box so they've already been shown to work with these methods and really
최신 모델은 즉시 사용 가능하므로 이미 이러한 방법으로 작동하는 것으로 나타났으며 실제로
with some manual modification configuration these models or these methods can be used with any models
일부 수동 수정 구성을 사용하면 이러한 모델 또는 이러한 방법을 모든 모델에 사용할 수 있습니다.
right or most models so here's a table where they've shown sort of what they've been able to do
오른쪽 또는 대부분의 모델이므로 여기에 그들이 할 수 있었던 일을 보여주는 표가 있습니다.
and so with mistro models or llama models you know these methods have been shown to work but with
따라서 mistro 모델이나 라마 모델의 경우 이러한 방법이 작동하는 것으로 나타났습니다.
again with configuration most models will work with the parameter efficient fine tuning method you
다시 구성을 사용하면 대부분의 모델은 매개변수 효율적인 미세 조정 방법으로 작동합니다.
choose and it's already been implemented thank you that concludes my presentation
선택하면 이미 구현되었습니다. 감사합니다. 프레젠테이션을 마치겠습니다.